Guide to the Chauncey M. Depew papers, 1856-1934 MS2095
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Newspapers and clippings, 1854-1930; MS2095 Series 5; 1 Linear feet (Box 41, Box 45)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Indiana, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Iowa, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Kansas, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Kentucky, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Louisiana, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Maine, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, (including editorial cartoon), Maryland, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Massachusetts, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 42)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Michigan, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 43)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Minnesota, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 44)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Mississippi, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 45)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Missouri, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 46)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Montana, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 47)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Nebraska, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 48)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Nevada, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 49)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, New Hampshire, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 50)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, New Jersey, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 51)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, New York, 02/18/1929 (Box 41, Folder 52)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, New York, 02/19/1929 (Box 41, Folder 53)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, New York, 02/20/1929-02/28/1929 (Box 41, Folder 54)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, New York, 03/1929-09/1930 (Box 41, Folder 55)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, North Carolina, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 56)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, North Dakota, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 57)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Ohio, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 58)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Oklahoma, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 59)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Oregon, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 60)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Pennsylvania, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 61)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Rhode Island, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 62)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, South Carolina, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 63)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, South Dakota, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 64)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Tennessee, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 65)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Texas, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 66)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Utah, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 67)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Vermont, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 68)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Virginia, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 69)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Washington, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 70)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, West Virginia, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 71)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Wisconsin, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 72)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Wyoming, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 73)
  - Various Clippings, primarily relating to Mrs. Depew's bequest to GWU, Ontario, Canada, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 74)
  - Various Clippings, original newspaper images, 1929-1930 (Box 41, Folder 75)
  - Newspapers and clippings, undated (Box 45)
  - Newspaper, The Yale Banner, (list of Societies - -CMD member as Junior in Linonian Society), 09/27/1854 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Illustration, Harper's Weekly, CMD addressing the Republican National Convention, 10/15/1881 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper, The Independent, New York, (Centennial of George Washington's Inauguration), 05/09/1889 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper, Eastern State Journal - Supplement, (George Washington Centennial), 1889 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper, The Mail and Express, (Lincoln's Birthday Commemoration), 02/13/1896 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper, Yale Alumni Weekly, 02/26/1896 (Box 45, Folder 6)
- Photographs, 1863-1923; MS2095 Series 6; 1 Linear feet (Box 42, Box 43)
  This series contains studio portraits of Depew as well as photographs of him within groups and at events, often where he was speaking. The photographs date from 1863-1923.
  Photographs are arranged first by type (Portraits, Groups, Events, Unidentified, and Oversized) and then chronologically.
  Some photographs are dated. For others, an approximate date was determined by publication dates of the photo in speech compilations or were estimated from age and dress.
  Unusual items include a set of photos of Depew with a child exploring a New York Central Rail Road locomotive (with an accompanying note which makes reference to motion pictures) and a series of snapshots of Depew with "His Excellency," an unidentified Asian man, mounted on black paper.
  - Photographs, undated (Box 42)
  - CMD portrait, Pach Bros., NY (in uniform?) Standing length, cut down, 1860 ca. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - CMD portrait, Pach Bros., NY (in uniform?) Standing length (6 copies), 1860 ca. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - CMD portrait, "The year Mr. Depew was elected Secretary of State (29 years old)" Standing length, 1863 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - CMD portrait, S.J. Thompson studio, Albany. Standing _ length pose, 1863 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - CMD portrait, Sarony studio, NY, 1870-1880 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - CMD portrait, Homberg v d Hohe, Germany, 1870-1890 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - CMD portrait, Homberg v d Hohe, Germany, 1870-1890 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - CMD portrait, Weil Bros., NY, _ length in uniform (Masonic?), 1870-1890 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - CMD portrait, Sarony studio, NY, 1878-1880 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - CMD portrait, Sarony studio, NY, 1878-1880 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - CMD portrait, Sarony studio, NY, 1880-1890 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - CMD portrait, President NYCRR, Sarony studio, NY, 1885 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - CMD portrait, President NYCRR, Sarony studio, NY, 1885 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - CMD portrait, Aime Dupont, NY 7 x 10, 1885 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - CMD portrait, Fredricks gallery, NY cabinet card (3 copies), 1887 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - CMD portrait, Fredricks gallery, NY cabinet card, 1887 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - CMD portrait, Fredricks gallery, NY 5 x 8_, 1887 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - CMD portrait, Fredricks gallery, NY 5 x 8_, 1887 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - CMD portrait, outdoors seated on steps, 1890-1900 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - CMD portrait, outdoors, standing at steps, 1890-1900 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - CMD portrait, Taber, NY, "Sculptograph" bas relief 5 copies, after 1896, undated (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - CMD portrait, Falk, NY, seated in office with book, 1897 (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - CMD portrait, Falk, NY, seated in office with book, 1897 (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - CMD portrait, Prince, Washington, DC, 1899-1912 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - CMD portrait, standing in office "taken on Mr. Depew's 89th birthday,", 1923 (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - CMD portrait, Pach Bros., NY, full length (poor condition), undated (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - CMD studio group with 4 other men, 4 women, Homberg v d Hohe, Germany, 1870-1890 (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - CMD outdoor group with 6 other men on steps, 1880-1890 (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - CMD outdoor group with men, women and children on steps, 1880-1890 (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - CMD at dinner party with 7 other men, 1870-1880 (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - CMD on platform with crowd, "Mr. Blaine at Hartford, Conn." Some individuals named on reverse., 11/01/1884 (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - CMD on platform w/ busts of Lincoln and unknown, Allen Ayrault, Galesburg, Ill. (note 44 star flag), 1890-1896 (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - CMD snapshot in garden, possibly at Peekskill estate, 1912-1928 (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - CMD speaking at dedication of statue of him at Depew Park, Peekskill, NY, 1918 (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - CMD speaking at unknown event, 1920-1930 (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - CMD with child on New York Central railroad engine. Set of 12 with note from Pitt P. Hand referring to motion pictures., 1921 (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - CMD riding bicycle along with unidentified man, undated (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - Unidentified young man, 1893 (Box 42, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified home in distance, 1893 (Box 42, Folder 39)
  - Unknown river scene, 1893 ca. (Box 42, Folder 40)
  - House with a four-pillared front. Possibly Depew home, Peekskill, undated (Box 42, Folder 41)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 43)
  - Oversized portrait of CMD, standing, in uniform, 1880-1890 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Oversized portrait of CMD, seated, reading, Prince studio, 1900-2000 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Photo series, mounted on paper, "Depew's Joke," Showing CMD with Asian companion, "His Excellency,", undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
- Genealogical and biographical publications, 1918-1934; MS2095 Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 44)
  There are two books in this series. One is a published genealogy of Depew and allied lines by William A. Eardeley, and one is a biography written by Willard Hayes Yeager, the first Chauncey M. Depew professor at The George Washington University. The biography includes a number of his speeches, some of which were previously unpublished.
  - Genealogical and biographical publications, undated (Box 44)
  - Chronology and Ancestry of Chauncey M. Depew, with 54 other Allied Families and an Appendix on the Hegeman Ancestry, compiled by William A. Eardeley, 1918 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Chauncey Mitchell Depew, the Orator, by Willard Hayes Yeager, 1934 (Box 44, Folder 2)
- Awards and certificates, 1854-1926; MS2095 Series 8; 1 Linear feet (Box 46, Box 45, Box 47)
  This series contains a number of oversized certificates of appointment, commission, and membership. It also includes a book Depew received as an award for public speaking while an undergraduate at Yale in 1854 as well as his diploma from Yale College in 1856. Dates range from 1854-1926.
  - Awards and certificates, undated (Box 45)
  - Certificate, Diploma, Bachelor's degree from Yale College, 1856 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Certificate, Commission as Judge Advocate, Colonel, 5th Division, National Guard of the State of New York, 07/14/1873 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Certificate of Membership, Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York, 05/07/1885 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Certificate, Commission as Aide-De-Camp, Grand Army of the Republic, Department of New York, 03/27/1888 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Certificate of membership, New York Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, 02/25/1890 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Certificates, Life memberships in The Lodge of Perfection, the Consistory of New York, the Council of Princes of Jerusalem, and The Chapter of Rose Croix of New York City, Scottish Rite, 02/17/1896 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Certificate of Appointment, CMD as delegate to the Illinois-Mississippi and International Exposition, June-November 1898, Omaha, Nebraska, 02/26/1898 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Certificate of Appointment, CMD as delegate to the Third National Peace Congress beginning 05/3 in Baltimore, Maryland, 04/20/1911 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Awards and certificates, undated (Box 46)
  - Award, Select British Eloquence, by Chauncey A. Goodrich, awarded to CMD at Yale for "excellence in declamation,", 1854 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Awards and certificates, undated (Box 47)
  - Certificate, Transfer of Membership, Grand Army of the Republic, 11/05/1926 (Box 47, Folder 1)
- Memorabilia, 1864-1926; MS2095 Series 9; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 45, Box 48, Box 47, Box 50, Box 49)
  This series contains memorabilia associated with events in Depew's life, including posters, menus, programs, booklets, postcards, sketches, Yale yearbooks, and a souvenir album of the Republican National Convention of 1892. Items date from 1864-1926.
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 45)
  - Resolution of World's Columbian Commission, expressing sympathy on death of CMD's wife, 1893 ca. (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Poster - Lotos Club "to our Chauncey" Menu of Dinner, 02/22/1896 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 47)
  - Pardon and release, of Jeremiah M'Cauley [McAuley], convicted of robbery, sentenced to Sing Sing Prison, CMD, Secretary of State. Framed copy sent to Depew in 1898, 03/08/1864 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Menu card, Mr. Seaver's Little Dinner to Mr. Justice Brady, Union Club, 02/11/1879 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Menu card, Lotos Club, Complimentary Dinner to Messrs. Arthur Sullivan and W.S. Gilbert, 11/08/1879 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Paas Festival (Easter), St. Nicholas Society, NY, 1879 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Souvenir program, Francesca daRimini, Star Theatre. Signed "Compliments of Anna Estelle Kidd" pink silk, 09/25/1883 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Souvenir program, Francesca daRimini, Star Theatre. Signed "Compliments of Anna Estelle Kidd" lavender silk, 09/25/1883 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Program with autographs, Union League Club Dinner Commemorating the Departure of the 20th US Colored Troops, 03/16/1886 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Menu program with notes, Dinner to Erastmus Wiman, Union League Club, NY, 03/26/1886 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Program with notes, 103rd Anniversary, Friendly Sons of St. Patrick, Delmonico's, 03/17/1887 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Booklet, A Christmas Sermon, by Phillips Brooks, 1890 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Programme, Pierce College of Business and Shorthand, 26th Class Graduating Exercises, 12/17/1891 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Souvenir Program, Dedication of New York State Building, World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 10/22/1892 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Booklet, The Symmetry of Life, by Phillips Brooks, 1892 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Programme, 9th Annual CMD Birthday Dinner, Montauk Club, Brooklyn, 04/21/1900 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Petition, Keeper and Surfmen of Short Beach Station, US Life Saving Service and others in support of a bill in Congress introduced by William A. Jones, VA, requesting CMD support. Also route slip, 01/17/1901 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Menu, Luncheon in Honor of President McKinley, Pan-American Exposition, Buffalo, NY (CMD note "the last public function which he attended"), 09/05/1901 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Booklet, 75th Anniversary, Peekskill Presbyterian Church, 1901 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Ledger sheet, CMD account with Flower & Co., 01/1902-04/1902 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Menu and seating chart, 12th Annual CMD Birthday Dinner, Montauk Club, Brooklyn, 04/25/1903 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Menu booklet with portraits of CMD and 05/Depew, 15th Annual CMD Birthday Dinner, Montauk Club, 04/22/1905 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Booklet, 100th Anniversary Historical Record, Peekskill Presbyterian Church, 1926 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Card with poem, owl version of "Love's Labor Lost,", undated (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Booklet, Cherry Valley Massacre Monument, undated (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Postcard, Chauncey M. Depew Monument, Depew Park, Peekskill, NY, undated (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Postcard, Peekskill Presbyterian Church, undated (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Portrait sketch, ink wash on cardboard, penciled notation " 1 - 12 years," reverse stamped "Property of NY Herald,", undated (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - Portrait sketch, ink wash on cardboard, penciled notation "3 - 20," reverse stamped "Property of NY Herald,", undated (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Portrait sketch, ink wash on cardboard, penciled notation "4," reverse stamped "Property of NY Herald,", undated (Box 47, Folder 29)
  - Request slips, to Superintendent of Documents, signed CMD (to have documents shipped to library), undated (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - Rubber stamp, CMD signature, undated (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 48)
  - Yearbook, Yale College, 1856 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 49)
  - Yearbook, Yale College, 1856 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 50)
  - Souvenir album of the Tenth National Republican Convention, Minneapolis, 06/1892 (Box 50, Folder 1)